KEVIN LEWIS

KPLewis33@gmail.com



Career Summary

I have over 23 years of experience in the fields of Advertising and Publishing Design & Production. I worked for over 15 years with the same company, including

over 3 years of managerial experience.

Software Knowledge

Proficient in Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Acrobat, Bridge, Pitstop, iPaper, Word, Excel, Constant Contact & Mirabel Magazine Manager. Familiar with WordPress, Dreamweaver, HTML5, CSS, Java Script, JQuery & UX/UI.

Professional Experience

- Production Manager, Publishers' Development Corporation Escondido, CA July 2007–March 2023
- In a leadership role, I oversaw the Production Department. My team worked to produce four print publications with worldwide distribution, in addition to trafficking over 200 ads per month for print & online exposure. We maintained a database of thousands of ad contracts & regularly generated performance reports on the print and digital products in which the ads appeared. Working with the Sales Department, the team helped our clients reach their advertising goals with everything from ad design to utilizing *Constant Contact* to deliver analytics for online advertising campaigns. Working with off-site printers, the team ensured that print products were delivered consistently, with the highest quality and efficiency possible. I also worked closely with the Accounting Department, generating client billing & reconciling vendor invoices to purchase orders. Other responsibilities included...
 - Providing support in the evaluation & negotiation of contractual agreements with print plants.
 - Setting the Production Schedules for all print and digital products and publications.
 - Monitoring of paper consumption, placing orders with paper mills when necessary.
 - Tracking & forecasting of production expenses; staying on-schedule & on-budget.
 - Maintaining the hygiene of a monthly promotional, mass-email list.
 - I developed an extensive "Procedures" manual, to aid in training of new employees.
 - I served on the company's 401K program review board, 2014–2023.
- Designer & Compliance Specialist, *Pindar Set/Yellow Book Company* San Diego, CA February 2000–April 2007

 I designed phone book ads, including digital art cleanup & manipulation. I consistently met daily production quotas & accuracy standards. The position required attention to detail, thorough knowledge of guidelines, problem-solving skills & the ability to communicate clearly. I also helped train new employees, which streamlined tasks & increased productivity.
- ♦ Assistant Manager, Cinemark Theaters Victorville, CA February 1997–December 1999

 16 months after my hire date, I was promoted from the floor staff to Assistant Manager. In this capacity, I led the staff in everyday operation, assisted customers, ran movie projectors, set employee schedules & handled concession/box office revenue. I conducted weekly inventory reviews & placed supply orders, which helped keep the theater stocked & running.

Education

AA in Graphic Design - Platt College, Ontario, CA-1999

Hobbies

I am working toward fluency in Spanish & French.
I enjoy exercising, playing guitar & chess.